Guide to the Irving Fisher Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- MICROFILM INVENTORY
  - Economic Essays, Vol. XVI: "General", 1921 - 1931
    - Index numbers
      - Letter to editor, replying to articles of 1923 Jan 27, Feb 3 & 10 ( TheStatist, London), 1923 March 31 (Box 4)
        - 4th letter to editor ( The Statist ), 1923 July 28 (Box 4)
      - Reply to Prof. Bowley's review of "The Making of Index Numbers" ( Economic Journal ), 1923 June (Box 4)
        - Reply to Prof. Young's review of same ( Quarterly Journal of Economics ), 1923 August (Box 4)
        - Reply to Carl Snyder's review of same ( American Economic Review ), 1923 December (Box 4)
      - "A Weekly Index Number of Wholesale Prices" ( Journal of Amer. Statis. Asso. ), 1923 September (Box 4)
      - "Mr. Undy Yule on Index Numbers" ( Journal of the Royal Statis. Society ), 1924 January (Box 4)
      - "Revision of the Weekly Index Number" ( Quarterly Publ. of Amer. Statis. Asso. ), 1924 September (Box 4)
      - "Index Numbers" ( Special Libraries, Prov. R.I.), 1925 March (Box 4)
      - "Revision of the Weekly Index Number" ( Journal of Amer. Statis. Asso. ), 1925 September (Box 4)
      - "New Index Numbers of Stock Sales and Prices" ( The Annalist, N.Y.C.), 1926 January 15 (Box 4)
      - "Revision of the Weekly Index Number" ( Journal of Amer. Statis. Asso. ), 1926 September (Box 4)
      - "Report to Date of the Weekly Index Number" ( Journal of Amer. Statis. Asso. ), 1927 June (Box 4)
      - "The 'Total Value Criterion': A New Principle in Index Number Construction" ( Journal of Amer. Statis. Asso. ), 1927 December (Box 4)
      - "Weekly Wholesale Index" ( Journal of Amer. Statis. Asso. ), 1928 December (Box 4)
      - 12. Bullion & Currency--What Free Coinage of Silver Would Mean, 1930 September (Box 4)
    - Calendar Reform:
      - Paragraph quoted in pamphlet: "Do We Need Calendar Reform," by George Eastman, 1927 (Box 4)
      - Interview re 13-month Calendar ( Register, N.H., Ct.), 1928 January 1 (Box 4)
      - "Advantages of 13-Month Year," extracts from address before International Congress on Accounting ( The American Accountant ), 1929 September 14 (Box 4)
        - "What is Calendar Reform?," address before same ( Proceedings of, same), 1930 (Box 4)
        - Extracts from same ( Incorporated Accountants' Journal, London, Eng.), 1929 October (Box 4)
    - General
      - Endorsement of The World Tomorrow, N.Y.C., 1927 February (Box 4)
      - Extracts from address before Elimination of Waste in Industry Conference, quoted in advertising of Nat'l Electric Light Asso., N.Y.C., 1927 April (Box 4)
        - Same
          - News, Dallas, Texas, 1927 April 10 (Box 4)
          - Inquirer, Phila., Pa., 1927 April 10 (Box 4)
          - Courier, Orange, N.J., 1927 August 2 (Box 4)
          - American Federationist, Wash., D.C., 1927 April 9 (Box 4)
      - "Knowledge, Enthusiasm & Self-Control needed in Industry," poster issued by Elliott, 1927 May (Box 4)
      - Statement re Coolidge's stand on 3rd term, made on "Mauretania" [sic] ( Herald-Tribune, N.Y.C.), 1927 August 18 (Box 4)
      - Telegram re selling campaign ( Remington Rand Bulletin, No. 1, N.Y.C.), 1927 summer (Box 4)
      - Report of address, Friends of Boys lunch, N.Y.C. ( Friends of Boys Mag., N.H., Ct.), 1927 (Box 4)
      - Statement in Nathan Straus birthday book, 1928 January 27 (Box 4)
      - Statement for Thanksgiving ( Christian Science Monitor, Boston), 1928 November 28 (Box 4)
      - "Urges Health Insurance," extracts from remarks before Amer. Asso. for Labor Legislation ( News, Wash., D.C.), 1927 December 28 (Box 4)
        - Same ( Times, Wash., D.C.), 1927 December 29 (Box 4)
      - "Interest Theory and Price Movements," discussion of Prof. Fetter's paper, Amer. Econ. Asso. ( Amer. Economic Review Supplement ), 1927 March (Box 4)
      - "A Statistical Method for Measuring 'Marginal Utility' and Testing the Justice of a Progressive Income Tax," reprint from Econ. Essays contributed in Honor of John Bates Clark, Macmillan, 1927 (Box 4)
      - "The Income Concept in the Light of Experience," English edition of article publ. in German ( Wieser Festschrift ), 1927 (Box 4)
      - Statement re Benjamin Javits' proposal for Industrial Coordination (booklet of Forbes Mag. ), 1928 (Box 4)
      - German reprint of above item ( Wieser Festschrift ), 1928 (Box 4)
        See also: series 7, reel 4, volume 16
      - Statement in symposium on How to Broaden Scope of Prosperity ( Christian Science Monitor ), 1928 February 29 (Box 4)
      - "The 'Business Cycle' Problem," a review of "The Road to Plenty," by W. T. Foster & W. Catchings ( The Saturday Review of Literature ), 1928 May 12 (Box 4)
        - Sep. reprint of same, 1928 (Box 4)
      - Statement re Prosperity, prepared for American-Poland Campaign ( Kurjer Poranny, Amer. Ed.), 1928 December 15 (Box 4)
      - Autobiography, prepared for Felix Meiner, Leipzig, 1929 (Box 4)
      - Statement re Too Many Non-Profit Sales ( News Record, N.Y.C.), 1929 March 8 (Box 4)
      - Comment on News Record, Dept: "The Market Viewpoint" ( News Record, N.Y.C.), 1929 March 25 (Box 4)
      - Reply to Inquiry re helping U.S. Farmer ( Records of Progress International Review, N.Y.C.), 1929 April (Box 4)
      - Statement re Sugar Tariff ( Statesville Record, Ark.), 1929 May 16 (Box 4)
      - Extracts from address on J. Willard Gibbs, Amer. Asso. for Advancement of Science, Des Moines, Iowa ( Press, Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1929 December 31 (Box 4)
      - Statement re Sunday School, 1930 (Box 4)
      - Extracts from J. W. Gibbs address ( Post, Baltimore, Md.), 1930 January 1 (Box 4)
      - Extracts from testimony at hearing before legislative Commission for Revision of Public Service Law ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1930 January 7 (Box 4)
        - Same
          - World, N.Y.C., & Journal of Commerce, 1930 January 7 (Box 4)
          - Commercial & Financial Chronicle, 1930 January 11 (Box 4)
          - Herald, Boston, & Herald-Tribune, N.Y.C., 1930 June 7 (Box 4)
      - "The Application of Mathematics to the Social Sciences," full address on J. W. Gibbs ( Bulletin of Amer. Math. Soc. ), 1930 April (Box 4)
      - "Sees Better Times Ahead," extracts from address to radio dealers & distributors ( Patriot, Jackson, Mich.), 1930 May 29 (Box 4)
      - Sep. reprint of above item from Bulletin of Amer. Math. Soc. ( Scientific Monthly ), 1930 June (Box 4)
      - "The Opportunity Theory of Interest" ( Univ. of Padua, Italy), 1930 (Box 4)
      - "Arthur Twining Hadley" ( Amer. Economic Rev. ), 1930 June (Box 4)
        - Reprint of same, 1930 (Box 4)
      - Review of "The Economics of Accountancy," by John B. Canning ( American Economic Review ), 1930 December (Box 4)
      - Interview re establishment of Central Bank of Issue in Argentina ( La Nacion, Buenos Aires), 1931 January 10 (Box 4)
      - "Translating Trust Service Into Economic and Social Values," address before Trust Co. division of Amer. Bankers Asso. ( Trust Companies, N.Y.C.), 1931 February (Box 4)
        - Same ( Proceedings of same), Conference, 1931 February 17-19 (Box 4)
        - Extracts from same
          - American Banker, N.Y.C., 1931 February 20 (Box 4)
          - Wall St. Journal, 1931 February 20 (Box 4)
          - Post, Charleston, S.C., 1931 February 20 (Box 4)
      - Letter to Pres. Hoover urging support of Wagner Public Employment Office bill, signed by 128 economists, etc. ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1931 February 16 (Box 4)
      - Letter to editor re City Manager plan ( Journal Courier, New Haven, Ct.), 1931 March (Box 4)
      - Letter to Pres. of International Chamber of Commerce, re lowering Tariff, with other signers ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1931 May 7 (Box 4)
      - Statement endorsing Community Chest ( Enquirer, Cleveland, Ohio), 1931 April 8 (Box 4)
      - Letter to editor re comments on statement by I.F. in weekly Index Number Service release ( Motion Picture Herald, N.Y.C.), 1931 May 23 (Box 4)
      - Letter protesting dismissal of Prof. Herbert Miller, Ohio State Univ., signed by 38 of Yale Faculty ( Record, Ridgeway, Pa.), 1931 June 8 (Box 4)
      - Extracts from address before Southwest Foreign Trade Conference, Oklahoma City, 1931 Jun 24 ( Cotton Trade Journal, New Orleans), 1931 June 27 (Box 4)
        - Same
          - Times, New Haven, Ct., 1931 June 25 (Box 4)
          - Republican, Waterbury, Ct., 1931 June 25 (Box 4)
          - Republican, Phoenix, Ariz., 1931 June 25 (Box 4)
          - Star, Shawnee, Okla., 1931 (Box 4)
          - Oklahoman, Oklahoma City, 1931 June 25 (Box 4)
          - Telegram, Youngstown, Ohio, 1931 June 25 (Box 4)
          - News, Shawnee, Okla., & Enquirer, Phila., 1931 June 25 (Box 4)
          - Christian Science Monitor, Boston, 1931 June 25 (Box 4)
          - Times, N.Y.C., 1931 June 25 (Box 4)
          - Journal, Knoxville, Tenn., 1931 June 28 - July 4 (Box 4)
      - Comment on Debt Relief Program ( Herald-Tribune, N.Y.C.), 1931 June 21 (Box 4)
      - Statement re London Conference ( News, Wash., D.C.), 1931 July 24 (Box 4)
      - "Business Cycles as Facts or Tendencies," reprint of essay for volume in honor of Prof. C.A. Verrijn Stuart, Haarlem, Holland, 1931 (Box 4)
  - Economic Essays, Vol. XVII: "Short Stories on Wealth", syndicated by Workers Education Bureau, 1926 - 1933
    For Chinese Translations of first 49 in Series of "Short Stories on Wealth" see oversize volume, No. 34 in Series of Bound Publications.
    - Mimeo Blurb about series, 1926 March (Box 5)
      - Photo accompanying same (Box 5)
    - 1. The Main Idea 9 Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen & Enginemen's Magazine ), 1926 February (Box 5)
      - Release of same, 1926 January 15 (Box 5)
    - 2. Capital Accounts ( Brotherhood of L. F. & E. Magazine ), 1926 March (Box 5)
      - Same ( Trades Union News ), 1926 February 25 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Labor Herald ), 1926 February 20 (Box 5)
    - 3. Income Accounts ( Brotherhood of L. F. & E. ), 1926 April (Box 5)
      - Same ( The Railway Clerk ), 1926 April (Box 5)
      - Same ( Trades Union News ), 1926 March 18 (Box 5)
    - 4. The Relation Between Capital & Income ( Brotherhood of L. F. & E. ), 1926 May (Box 5)
    - 5. What Money Is Not ( Trades Union News ), 1926 May 27 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Brotherhood of L. F. & E. ), 1926 June (Box 5)
      - Same ( Advocate ), 1926 May 29 (Box 5)
    - 6. What Money Is and Is For ( Trades Union News ), 1926 June 24 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Brotherhood of L. F. & E. ), 1926 July (Box 5)
      - Same ( Record ), 1926 June 23 (Box 5)
    - 7. Credit Currency ( Trades Union News ), 1926 July 22 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Brotherhood of L. F. & E. ), 1926 August 19 (Box 5)
    - 8. The Purchasing Power of Money ( Trades Union News ), 1926 August 19 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Brotherhood of L. F. & E. ), 1926 September (Box 5)
    - 9. What Fixes the Purchasing Power of the Dollar? ( Brotherhood of L. F. & E. ), 1926 October (Box 5)
      - Same ( Trades Union News ), 1926 September 23 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Tribune ), 1926 October 15 (Box 5)
    - 10. How Inflation and Deflation Work ( Brotherhood ), 1926 November (Box 5)
    - 11. The Flowing Stream of Money & Goods ( Brotherhood ), 1926 December (Box 5)
      - Same ( Tribune ), 1926 November (Box 5)
    - Progress and Depressions--and our American Dollar, 1927 January (Box 5)
      - Same ( Record ), 1927 April 6 (Box 5)
    - 13. Supply & Demand ( Brotherhood of L.F. & E. ), 1927 February (Box 5)
    - 14. Supply & Demand, Contd. ( Brotherhoodof L. F. & E. ), 1927 March (Box 5)
      - Same ( Record ), 1927 May 18 (Box 5)
    - 15. Changes in Supply & Demand ( Union News ), 1927 March 25 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Brotherhood of L. F. & E. ), 1927 April (Box 5)
    - 16. What's Back of Demand? ( Brotherhood of L. F.& E. ), 1927 May (Box 5)
      - Same ( Record ), 1927 August 13 (Box 5)
    - 17. The Relation of Want & Demand ( Brotherhood ), 1927 June (Box 5)
    - 18. The Influences Behind Supply ( Brotherhood ), 1927 July (Box 5)
    - 19. Monopoly Price ( Brotherhood of L. F. & E. ), 1927 August (Box 5)
    - 20. Cut-Throat Competition ( Brotherhood ), 1927 September (Box 5)
      - Same ( Union News ), 1927 August 26 (Box 5)
      - Same ( The Lather ), 1927 October (Box 5)
    - 21. Cut-Throat Competition Leads to Monopoly ( The Railway Clerk ), 1927 October (Box 5)
      - Same ( The Lather ), 1927 November (Box 5)
    - 22. The Future, Not the Past, Rules Value ( Lather ), 1927 December (Box 5)
    - 23. The Riddle of Interest ( Labor Journal ), 1927 November 28 (Box 5)
      - Same ( The Lather ), 1928 January (Box 5)
    - 24. Is Interest Taking Wrong? ( Advertiser ), 1928 January 5 (Box 5)
      - Same ( The Lather ), 1928 February (Box 5)
    - Series B
      - 25. #1: Some Wrong Explanations of Interest ( The Lather ), 1928 January 15 (Box 5)
      - 26. #2: Real Interest and Money ( Lather ), 1928 April (Box 5)
      - 27. #3: Impatience to Spend ( Lather ), 1928 May (Box 5)
      - 28. #4: The Personal Reasons for Impatience ( The Lather ), 1928 June (Box 5)
      - 29. #5: The Impersonal Factors in Impatience ( The Lather ), 1928 July (Box 5)
      - 30. #6: How Impatience Influences Interest ( The Lather ), 1928 August (Box 5)
      - 31. #7: Opportunity for Investment ( The Lather ), 1928 September (Box 5)
      - 32. #8: Before Leaving the Subject of Prices ( The Lather ), 1928 October (Box 5)
      - 33. #9: Distribution ( The Lather ), 1928 November (Box 5)
      - 34. #10: Rent ( The Lather ), 1928 December (Box 5)
      - 35. #11: Land Rent ( The Lather ), 1929 January (Box 5)
      - 36. #12: Wages ( The Lather ), 1929 February (Box 5)
    - Series C
      - 37. #1: The Demand for Labor ( Lather ), 1929 March (Box 5)
      - 38. #2: Wages and Total Earnings of Labor ( The Lather ), 1929 April (Box 5)
      - 39. #3: Labor Efficiency ( The Lather ), 1929 May (Box 5)
      - 40. #4: Wages & Employers' Profits ( The Lather ), 1929 June (Box 5)
      - 41. #5: Profits & Wages ( The Lather ), 1929 July (Box 5)
      - Same ( Union News ), 1929 August 30 (Box 5)
      - 42. #6: The Capitalist-Employer ( The Lather ), 1929 August (Box 5)
      - 43. #7: The Capitalist-Employer, Contd. ( The Lather ), 1929 September (Box 5)
      - 44. #8: Personal Distribution ( Lather ), 1929 October (Box 5)
      - 45. #9: National Wealth or Poverty ( Lather ), 1929 November (Box 5)
      - 46. #10: Population & Poverty ( The Lather ), 1929 December (Box 5)
      - 47. #11: Population & Poverty, Contd., Lather, 1930 January (Box 5)
      - 48. #12: Polulation & Wealth ( The Lather ), 1930 February (Box 5)
        - Same ( American Constitution ), 1930 January (Box 5)
        - Same ( Labor Journal ), 1929 December 27 (Box 5)
    - 49. Distribution ( The Lather ), 1930 March (Box 5)
    - 50. The Effect of Thrift & Thriftlessness on Distribution, The Lather ), 1930 March (Box 5)
    - 51. Causes of Unequal Distribution ( Lather ), 1930 April (Box 5)
    - 52. How Rich Can a Man Become? ( The Lather ), 1930 May (Box 5)
    - 53. The Limits of Accumulating Fortunes ( Lather ), 1930 June (Box 5)
    - 54. Mobility of Distribution ( The Lather ), 1930 July (Box 5)
    - 55. A "Word Picture" of Distribution ( Lather ), 1930 August (Box 5)
    - 56. Inflation & Deflation an Economic Disease ( The Lather ), 1930 October (Box 5)
    - 57. Big Harm from Unstable Dollar ( The Lather ), 1930 November (Box 5)
      - Same ( The Lather ), 1930 December (sic) (Box 5)
    - 58. Evils of Inflation, release, 1930 October 1 (Box 5)
    - 59. Too Much Money ( The Lather ), 1931 January (Box 5)
    - 60. [no title] (Box 5)
    - 61. How Inflation and Deflation Affect Investors, release, 1931 January 1 (Box 5)
      - Same ( The Lather ), 1931 February (Box 5)
      - Same ( Trades Council Union News ), 1931 January 23 (Box 5)
    - 62. The Unstable Dollar and Unstable Employment ( The Lather ), 1931 March (Box 5)
    - 63. Stable Money Important to Labor ( Lather ), 1931 April (Box 5)
    - 64. Review of Harm Done by Inflation and Deflation ( The Lather ), 1931 May (Box 5)
    - 65. How Business Men Can Safeguard Against Unstable Money ( The Lather ), 1931 June (Box 5)
    - 66. [no title] (Box 5)
    - 67. Stabilizing the Dollar, release, 1931 July 4 (Box 5)
      - Same ( The Lather ), 1931 July (Box 5)
    - 68. Banks & Govt. Can Help Stabilization, release, 1931 September 1 (Box 5)
    - 69. How to Stabilize, release, 1931 October 3 (Box 5)
    - 70. Summary on Unstable Money ( The Lather ), 1931 December (Box 5)
    - 71. Peace & Prosperity ( The Lather ), 1932 January (Box 5)
    - 72. The Economic Importance of World Peace & Disarmament ( The Lather ), 1932 February (Box 5)
    - 73. Disease as Economy Waste ( The Lather ), 1932 March (Box 5)
    - 74. Conservation ( The Lather ), 1932 April (Box 5)
    - 75. Science & Invention ( The Lather ), 1932 May (Box 5)
    - 76. Saving Waste in Industry ( The Lather ), 1932 June (Box 5)
    - 77. The Tariff ( The Lather ), 1932 July (Box 5)
    - 78. The "Single Tax," release, 1932 July 16 (Box 5)
    - 79. Social Insurance ( The Lather ), 1932 September (Box 5)
    - 80. Minimum Standards, release, 1932 October 15 (Box 5)
    - 81. The Relation of Health to Work, release, 1932 November 19 (Box 5)
    - 82. Socialism & Communism ( The Lather ), 1933 January (Box 5)
      - Same ( Painter &Decorator ), 1933 February (Box 5)
    - 83. Inequality of Distribution, release, 1933 January 7 (Box 5)
    - 84. Remedies for Wrong Distribution, release, 1933 January 21 (Box 5)
      - Same ( The Lather ), 1933 February (Box 5)
    - 85. Economics is the Science of Wealth ( Lather ), 1933 March (Box 5)
    - 86. Concluding Summary, release, 1933 March 4 (Box 5)
      - Same ( The Lather ), 1933 April (Box 5)
  - Economic Essays, Vol. XVIII: "Reflation" (, 1931 - 1933
    - Omitted from previous volumes
      - Goldsborough speech quoting letters favoring Fisher plan for Stabilization ( Congressional Record ), 1922 August 16 (Box 5)
        - 2nd Goldsborough speech on same ( Congressional Record ), 1922 September 16 (Box 5)
      - "Conditions better," interview ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1931 September 26 (Box 5)
      - Statement re Short selling ( Journal, Moundsville, W. Va., and Knickerbocker Press, Albany, N.Y.), 1931 October 3 and 1931 October 4 (Box 5)
        - Similar statement (( Manitoba Free Press, Winnipeg), 1931 October 6 (Box 5)
      - Interview re Depression ( Times, Buffalo, N.Y.), 1931 October 5 (Box 5)
      - Comment on Swope plan to stabilize ( Christian Science Monitor, Boston, Mass.), 1931 October 5 (Box 5)
      - 1st installment interview by Boyd Lewis, syndicated by United Press ( World-Telegram and Press, Fort Worth, Texas), 1931 October 7 and 1931 October 9 (Box 5)
        - 2nd installment of same ( New Era, Lancaster, Pa.), 1931 October 10 (Box 5)
        - 3rd installment of same ( News, Kenosha, Wis., and Investment News, N.Y.C.), 1931 October 12 and 1931 October 10 (Box 5)
      - "Dear Gold Threatens Gold Standard" ( New Engalnd Purchaser, Boston, Mass.), 1931 November (Box 5)
      - Extracts from speech, Amer. Statis. Asso. dinner, 1931 Oct 26 ( News-Press, St. Joseph, Mo.), 1931 November 9 (Box 5)
      - "Income" ( Encyclopaedia of Soc. Sci. ), 1932 (Box 5)
    - Quote re Depression ( Corriere Della Sera, Milan), 1932 February 13 (Box 5)
    - Account of Rollins College address ( Times Union and Post, Bridgeport, Conn.), 1932 February 22 and 1932 February 23 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Globe Democrat, St. Louis. Mo.; Times, N.Y.C.; and Gazette, Worcester), 1932 Feb 22; ( Republican, Scranton, Pa.), 1932 February 24 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Journal, Corry, Pa., and, Orlando, Fla.), 1932 February 24 and 1932 February 27 (Box 5)
    - Address before Com. of 100, Miami Beach, 1932 March 1 (Box 5)
    - Statement before Com. on Banking & Currency, 72nd Congress,, Govt. Printing Office, 1932 March 28-291932 (Box 5)
    - Statement before Com. on Ways & Means,, 72nd Congress, Govt. Printing Office, 1932 April 27, 28, 291932 (Box 5)
    - "Urges Stabilized Dollar" ( Star, Wash., D.C.), 1932 March 28 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Sun, N.Y.C.), 1932 March 28 (Box 5)
      - Same ( U.S. Daily, Wash., D.C.), 1932 March 29 (Box 5)
    - "Deposit Guarantee Will Aid Confidence," same, 1932 March 31 (Box 5)
    - "Is There a Cure for Deflation?" ( Review of Reviews ), 1932 April (Box 5)
    - "Urges Reflation" ( Record, Phila., Pa.), 1932 April 9 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Free Press, Detroit, and Tribune, Marysville, O.), 1932 April 9 (Box 5)
    - Editorial re I.F. on Bank Deposit Guarantee ( Tribune, Sioux City, Iowa), 1932 April 18 (Box 5)
    - Comment on Rev. of Rev. article by Arthur Brisbane ( Examiner, Los Angeles, Calif.), 1932 April 21 (Box 5)
    - Similar letter to Editor (Montreal),; reprinted ,)--13, 1932 April 23 (Box 5)
    - Prediction re Business Trend ( Post, Denver, Col.), 1932 May 14 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Daily Province, Vancouver, Canada), 1932 May 14 (Box 5)
    - "Backs Price Bill" ( Journal, N.Y.C.), 1932 May 14 (Box 5)
    - Summary of statement before Banking & Currency Com., in "Mirrors" ( Star, Montreal, Canada), 1932 May 16 (Box 5)
    - "Supports Bond Issue" ( Advocate, Bellville, Ill., and Commercial News, Danville, Ill.), 1932 May 16 (Box 5)
    - "Shall We Devaluate the Dollar?" (in symposium of Commerce & Finance, N.Y.C.), 1932 May 18 (Box 5)
      - Quote from same ( Eagle, Pittsfield, Mass.), 1932 May 27 (Box 5)
    - Summary of testimony before Senate Banking & Currency Committee ( Commercial & Financial Chronicle ), 1932 May 21 (Box 5)
    - "What Can Congress Do," sample Index No. Institute Release, 1932 November 26 (Box 5)
      - List of Subscribers to same, 1932 November 28 (Box 5)
      - German Trans. of same release, Bern, Switz., 1932 December 4 (Box 5)
    - Book Review of "The Revision of the Price Index Numbers," by T. Sheng ( Journal of Amer. Statis. Asso. ), 1932 December (Box 5)
    - "Schwundgeld?" ( Das Tage Buch, Munich), 1932 December 24 (Box 5)
    - Account of Stamp Scrip Plan ( Christian Science Monitor, Boston, Mass.), 1932 December 21 (Box 5)
    - Reprint of "Schwundgeld?" ( Tagblatt, Prague), 1932 December 28 (Box 5)
      See also: series 7, reel 5, volume 18
    - "Favors Stamp Scrip" ( Post, Cincinnati, O.), 1932 December 30 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Times-Star, Cincinnati, O.), 1932 December 30 (Box 5)
    - "Compensated Dollar," in German ( Die Neue Welt, Essen, Germany), 1933 January (Box 5)
    - 1933 Viewed by 3 Economists ( Ice Cream Field ), 1933 January (Box 5)
    - "Urges Reflation" ( Record, Meriden, Conn.), 1933 February 6 (Box 5)
    - "Favors Stamped Scrip for Reflation" ( Herald-Tribune, New York, N.Y.), 1933 February 7 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Republican, Waterbury, Conn.), 1933 February 7 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Capital Journal, Pierre, S.D.), 1933 February 24 (Box 5)
    - Letter to Editor re Stamped Scrip ( New Republic, New York, N.Y.), 1933 February 22 (Box 5)
      - 2nd letter re same ( New Republic ), 1933 March 15 (Box 5)
      - 3rd letter re same ( New Republic ), 1933 April 12 (Box 5)
    - Quote re Stamp Scrip ( Commercial & Financial Chronicle, New York), 1933 March 4 (Box 5)
    - "Statistics in the Service of Economics" ( Journal of Amer. Statistical Asso. ), 1933 March (Box 5)
    - "The Relation of Employment to the Price Level" ( Stabilization of Employment, Ed. by C.F. Roos), 1933 (Box 5)
    - "Reflation Backed" ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1933 April 23 (Box 5)
      - Same (Box 5)
        - Register, New Haven, Ct., 1933 April 23 (Box 5)
        - Journal, Corry, Pa., 1933 April 24 (Box 5)
        - Daily News, Chicago, Ill., 1933 April 25 (Box 5)
      - Another ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1933 April 26 (Box 5)
      - Editorial re same ( Index-Journal, Greenwood, S.C.), 1933 April 28 (Box 5)